// breaking bad trivia game

// audio files object
var audio = {
    audGameIntro: "./assets/audio/breaking-bad-intro.mp3",
    audRightAns: "./assets/audio/youre-god-damn-right.mp3",
    audWrongAns: "./assets/audio/whatever-man.mp3",
    audSkipQuest: "./assets/audio/whatup-biatch.mp3"
}

// question/answers object
var QAobject = [
    {
        question: "What song plays in Saul Goodmanâ€™s waiting room?",
        correctAnswer: "America the Beautiful",
        answers: ["America the Beautiful", "This Land is Your Land", "Livin On a Prayer", "MMMbop"],
        gif: "<img src='./assets/images/1_saulGoodman.gif'/>",
    },
    {
        question: "What ailment does Walter White battle?",
        correctAnswer: "lung cancer",
        answers: ["lung cancer", "Huntington's disease", "multiple personality disorder", "meth addiction"],
        gif: "<img src='./assets/images/2_waltChemo.gif'/>",
    },
    {
        question: "What is Walt's most-used alias?",
        correctAnswer: "Heisenberg",
        answers: ["Heisenberg", "Hitchcock", "Kennedy", "Escobar"],
        gif: "<img src='./assets/images/3_heisenberg.gif'/>",
    },
    // "questD": {
    //     question: "Who wrote the poem that got Walt busted by his brother-in-law?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["Walt Whitman", "Robert Frost", "Emily Dickinson", "TS Eliot"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/4_waltWhitman.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questE": {
    //     question: "Where is the White family home located?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["Albuquerque", "Santa Fe", "Phoenix", "Los Cruces"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/5_whitesHouse.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questF": {
    //     question: "Actor RJ Mitte, who plays Walt Jr, has cerebral palsy in real life",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["True", "False"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/6_RJmitte.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questG": {
    //     question: "What nickname does Walt Jr like to be called?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["Flynn", "Slick", "Axle", "Combo"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/7_flynn.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questH": {
    //     question: "What company did Walter White co-found with Elliot Schwartz?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["Grey Matter", "Beneke Fabricators", "Brain Matter", "Badman Pharma"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/8_greyMatter.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questI": {
    //     question: "How do Walt and Jesse know each other?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["Walt was Jesse's high school chem teacher", "Jesse is Walt's nephew", "Walt is Jesse's boss at the carwash", "Jesse was Walt's pizza delivery guy"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/9_teacher.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questJ": {
    //     question: "What color is Walt's meth?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["blue", "green", "white", "pink"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/10_blueIce.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questK": {
    //     question: "What restaurant franchise does Mr Fring own?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["Los Pollos Hermanos", "Popeye's", "El Pollo Loco", "Quiero Campana de Tacos"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/11_losPollos.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questL": {
    //     question: "In the episode Salud, what gift does Mr Fring give Don Eladio?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["Zafiro Anejo", "Entrepierna de Fuego", "Rolex", "a kiss"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/12_tequila.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questM": {
    //     "q": "Mike Ehrmantraut develops and unlikely fondness for whom?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["Jesse Pinkman", "Walter White", "Tuco Salamanco", "Lydia Rodarte-Quayle"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/13_mikeJesse.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questN": {
    //     question: "Whose throat does Mr Fring cut in front of Walt, Jesse, and Mike?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["Victor", "Nacho Varga", "Gale Boetticher", "Hector Salamanca"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/14_victorDeath.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questO": {
    //     question: "Who was not a member of Jesse's crew?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["Tortuga", "Beaver", "Skinny Pete", "Combo"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/15_tortuga.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questP": {
    //     question: "What is Mr Fring's first name?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["Gustavo", "Victor", "Raymond", "Gonzo"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/16_gus.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questQ": {
    //     question: "What is the name of Walt's wife?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["Skyler", "Holly", "Flynn", "Marie"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/17_skyler.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questR": {
    //     question: "Which of the following words is not in Jesse's daily vocabulary?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["Salud", "Yo", "Bitch", "Like"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/18_yoBitch.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questS": {
    //     question: "Who shot Gale Boetticher?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]", 
    //     answers: ["Jesse Pinkman", "Walter White", "Mr Fring", "Hank Schrader"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/19_galeDeath.gif'/>",   
    // },
    // "questT": {
    //     question: "Which location was not one of Walt's cook sites?",   
    //     correctAnswer: "ansAll[0]",
    //     answers: ["the chicken factory farm", "other people's houses", "Jesse's basement", "an RV"],
    //     gif: "<img src='./assets/images/20_chickenFarm.gif'/>",   
    // },
];

// global variables
    var gameContent; //for Q&A jumbotron to appear after aboutGame disappears on click
    var currentQuestion = ""; //current question on screen
    var randoSortedAnswers = ""; //to randomly sort answer selection being displayed for the current question on screen
    var rightAnswer = ""; //so the computer knows which answer is the correct one for the current question on screen
    var wrongAnswers = ""; //so the computer knows which answers are incorrect for the current question on screen
    var scoreWins = 0; //store points for player's right answers
    var scoreLosses = 0; //store points for player's wrong answers
    var scoreMissed = 0; //store points for player's missed answers
    var timer; //30-second countdown timer for each question

    //     var container = document.getElementById("quizContainer"); //don't think i need this
    // var container = document.getElementById("gameContainer");
    // var questionEl = document.getElementById("question");
    //     var opt1 = document.getElementById("opt1"); //don't think i need this
    // var answers = document.getElementById("answers");
    // var QAobject = QAobject.length;
    // var nextButton = document.getElementById("nextButton")
    // var resultCont = document.getElementById("result")

    var qCounter = 0;    //for which question is being displayed currently
    var jumbotron = $("#gameContainer");
    var timerStart = 30;

// start function
function start() {
    //initial load settings
    timerStart = 30;
    scoreWins = 0;
    scoreLosses = 0;
    scoreMissed = 0;

    currentQuestion = "",
    timer = timerStart,
    // timer();

    // intro audio
    console.log("audio", audio.audGameIntro);
    var sound = new Audio("./assets/audio/breaking-bad-intro.mp3");
    sound.play();

    // hide aboutGame div after on click
    $(".aboutGame").hide()

    // call function loadQuestion
    loadQuestion();
};

// timer for each question function, 
function timer() {

    var timerStart = 30;

    //  Variable that will hold our interval ID when we execute
    //  the "run" function
    var intervalId;

    //  When the stop button gets clicked, run the stop function.
    $("#stop").on("click", stop);

    //  When the resume button gets clicked, execute the run function.
    $("#resume").on("click", run);

    //  The run function sets an interval
    //  that runs the decrement function once a second.
    //  *****BUG FIX******** 
    //  Clearing the intervalId prior to setting our new intervalId will not allow multiple instances.
    function run() {
    clearInterval(intervalId);
    intervalId = setInterval(decrement, 1000);
    }

    //  The decrement function.
    function decrement() {

    //  Decrease timerStart by one.
    timerStart--;

    //  Show the timerStart in the #show-timerStart tag.
    $("#show-timerStart").html("<h2>" + timerStart + "</h2>");


    //  Once timerStart hits zero...
    if (timerStart === 0) {

    //  ...run the stop function.
    stop();

    //  Alert the user that time is up.
    alert("Time Up!");
    }
    }

    //  The stop function
    function stop() {

    //  Clears our intervalId
    //  We just pass the name of the interval
    //  to the clearInterval function.
    clearInterval(intervalId);
    }

    //  Execute the run function.
    run();


    // setTimeout(thirtySeconds, 1000 * 30);
    // setTimeout(timeUp, 1000 * 30);

    // function thirtySeconds() {
    //     // in the element with an id of time-left add an h2 saying About 5 Seconds Left!
    //     // console log 5 seconds left
    //     $("#time-left").append("<h2>About 5 Seconds Left!</h2>");
    //     console.log("5 seconds left");
    // }

    // function timeUp() {
    //     // in the element with an id of time-left add an h2 saying Time's Up!
    //     // console log done
    //     console.log("done");
    //     $("#time-left").append("<h2>Time's Up!</h2>");
    //     console.log("time is up");

    //     console.log("audio", audio.audSkipQuest);
    //     var sound = new Audio("./assets/audio/whatup-biatch.mp3");
    //     sound.play();
    // }
}


//load first question
function loadQuestion() {
    $('.domQuestion').text(QAobject[qCounter].question);
    $('.domAnswer1').text(QAobject[qCounter].answers[0]);
    $('.domAnswer2').text(QAobject[qCounter].answers[1]);
    $('.domAnswer3').text(QAobject[qCounter].answers[2]);
    $('.domAnswer4').text(QAobject[qCounter].answers[3]);
}


    // matches player's selection w correct answer function, gifs      
    // what happens when they have a correct answer?
    // what happens when they have an incorrect answer?

    // next question button in case they don't want to wait for timer
    // next question, resets timer for next question
    // push questions/answers

    // increment qCounter and load next question????
    // check to see if there are any more questions left, else...           
    // if qcounter is < qaobject.length
    // end game function
    // hide qa content div
    // display summary


    // scoreboard function 


    function end() {
        // reset    
    }




    // click events
    $("#startBtn").on('click', function () {
        console.log("clicked");
        start();
    });
    $(document).on('click', ".answer", function () {
        var playerSelection = $(this).text();
        console.log("player selection", playerSelection);
        if (playerSelection === QAobject[qCounter].correctAnswer) {
            console.log("correct answer");

        } else {
            console.log("wrong answer")
        }
    });